Guide to the System Development Foundation (Palo Alto, Calif.) Records, 1957-1993
Department of Special Collections
- Series 5. Subject Files of People and Places
  - Subseries A. Reference and Information files
    - Subsubseries 2. Reference files, ca. 1981-1984
      - Colgate University (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Columbia University (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Computer Museum: Gordon and Gwen Bell (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - The Conference Board (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Coopersmith, Jonathan (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Council on Library Resources (CLR) (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Courant Institute (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Creative Think: Roger von Oech (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Cronin, Blaise (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Crooks, Susan (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Cutler, Preston (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Dannenberg, Roger B. (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - DARPA meeting notes. Kahn (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Davidson, Howard L. (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - De Gennaro, Richard: University of Pennsylvania #1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - De Gennaro, Richard: University of Pennsylvania #2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - De Jong, Peter #1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - De Jong, Peter #2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - De Maine, P.A.D. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Denelcor: Alex Layman (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Denyer, Peter B. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Diabetes Research (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Digital Equipment Corporation (DEC) (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Drexler, K. Eric: MIT, Space Systems Laboratory (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Duda, Richard D. (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Duke University (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Dutcher, Richard F. (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Exxon Foundation (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Fadiman, Clifton (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Fairchild Lab #1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Fairchild Lab #2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Fairthorne, Robert A. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Feldman, J. A.: Rochester University #1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Feldman, J. A.: Rochester University #2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Feldman, Stuart I. (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Florida State University, Center for Music Research (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Foreign Grantees (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Forrester, Jay: MIT (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Foundation Center, The (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Foundations (General): Funds & Other Funding Sources (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Fox, Renee C. (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Freedman, D. (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Freisen, W. Otto: Ohio (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Froelich, Leopold (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Fry, C.: MIT, Computer Music (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Fujimura, Osamu #1 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Fujimura, Osamu #2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Funt, Brian V. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Gallagher & Wise (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Gaver, Donald P. (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Gentleman, W. Morven (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Gerson, Eli (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Gifts in kind (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Glaser, Edward (Ted) (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Godfrey, Kent: Pyramid. (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Godfrey, Dr. Michael: Sperry-Univac #1 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Godfrey, Dr. Michael: Sperry-Univac #2 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Godfrey, Dr. Michael: Sperry-Univac #3 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Golden, William (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Goldin-Meadow, Susan (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Gordon, William (Bill) (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Government & Capital Markets (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Greene, Peter: Illinois Institute of Technology (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Griss, M. L: University of Utah (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Hale, Douglas (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Harvard University (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Haskins Laboratories: Alvin Liberman (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Heilbron, John L. (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Hendrix & Sacerdoti (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Hendry, David: ULTRA (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Higginbotham, James (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Hillis, Danny: MIT (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Hirst, William (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - History of Science (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Hobbs, Jerry: SRI (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Holmes, Heather (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Hopfield, J. J. (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Horovitz, Mark W. (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Huddleson, Edwin (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Hudspeth, A. James (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Hughes, Thomas P. (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Hunt, Morton (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Hutchins, Edwin: UCSD (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Information Industry Association (IIA) (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Institute for Scientific Information (ISI) (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Indiana University #1 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Indiana University #2 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Indiana University #3 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Information Processing Systems (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Information Science #1 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Information Science #2 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - L'Institute de Recherches et de Coordination Acoustique/Musique (IRCAM) (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - International Computers Limited (ICL) (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Japanese Meetings #11984 Oct. (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Japanese Meetings #21984 Oct. (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Japanese Meetings #31984 Oct. (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Japanese Meetings #41984 Oct. (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Japanese Meetings #51984 Oct. (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Karl, Barry and Katz, Stanley: University of Chicago, History of Corporate Philanthropy #1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Karl, Barry and Katz, Stanley: University of Chicago, History of Corporate Philanthropy #2 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Kaye, H. L. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Kennaway, J. R. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Keppel, Francis: Harvard (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - King, Donald #1 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - King, Donald #2 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Kinzel, Augustus (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Klaappholz, David (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Klahr, David (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Kling, Rob (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Knowlton, Roberta B. (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Knuth, Donald #1 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Knuth, Donald #2 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Knuth, Donald #3 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Kohler, Robert E. (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Konolige, Kurt (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Koret Foundation (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Kornfeld, William: MIT (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Kruskal, William: University of Chicago #1 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Kruskal, William: University of Chicago #2 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Kruskal, William: University of Chicago #3 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Kruskal, William: University of Chicago #4 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Kruskal, William: University of Chicago #5 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Kruskal, William: University of Chicago #6 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Kruskal, William: University of Chicago #7 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Kruskal, William: University of Chicago #8 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Kruskal, William: University of Chicago #9 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Kruskal, William: University of Chicago #10 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Kuklick, Henrika (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Lansky, Paul & Steiglitz, Kenneth (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Laser Microbeam Program (LAMP), NIH-UCI (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Latour, Bruno (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Libraries (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Library Science (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Lisanti, Vincent F and Kurt Enslein (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - LISP (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Losleben, P. (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Lyon, Richard F. (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Malsberg, Christoph von der: Neurobiology (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - March, James (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Marconi Foundation (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Marr, D.C. (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - Matthews, Max: Bell Labs (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - The Maxima Corporation: Joshua Smith (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Microelectronics & Computer Tech Corp. (MCC) #1 (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Microelectronics & Computer Tech Corp. (MCC) #2 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - McGill, R.: Bell Labs (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Michod, Richard E.: University of Arizona (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Milenkovic, Paul (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Minsky, Marvin (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) #1 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) #2 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) #3 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) #4 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - MIT, Center for Computational Research (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - MIT Press (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Moore, Richard: UCSD (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Morrisett, Lloyd (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Moser, Claus, "Statistics and Public Policy" (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Moses, Lincoln (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - National Computer Graphics Association (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - National Science Foundation #1 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - National Science Foundation #2 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - National Science Foundation. Initiative (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - New York University (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - New York University. Sesquicentennial (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - NFAIS (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - Notkin, David #1 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Notkin, David #2 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Notkin, Debbie (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - NRC (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - ONR-Cognitive Science #1 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - ONR-Cognitive Science #2 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - ONR-Cognitive Science #3 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - ONR-Cognitive Science #4 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Oxford Press (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Palo Alto Medical Foundation (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Paul, Richard (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Perkel, Donald (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Perlman, Gary (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Pittsburgh State University (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Pixel (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Polytechnic Institute of New York (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Pratt, Vaughn (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Pregibon, Daryl (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Princeton University (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Public Management Institute (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Quick, Allen (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Rand Corporation #1 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Rand Corporation #2 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Reitman, Walter R. (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Research program drafts: "Tab C" (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Resnikoff, Howard L. #1 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - Resnikoff, Howard L. #2 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - Richards, Whitman: MIT PR (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - Roberts, Walter Orr (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - Robotics (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - Romansky Symposium (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Rosenberg, Charles E. (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - Rubin, Steven M. (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - Salisbury, Ken (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - Salk Institute (Box 16, Folder 17)
      - Schroeder, Manfred. (Box 16, Folder 18)
      - Seitz, Charles: Cal Tech (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Shaw, Edward: RLG (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Simon, Herbert: Carnegie-Mellon University (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Smith, Brian (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - SRI International (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Stanford (General) (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Stautner, John (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Stigler, Stephen M. (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Stine, Harry (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Sugarman, Myron (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Survey Methodological Information System (SMIS) (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Swazey, Judith P. (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Tanur, Judith (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Tenenbaum, Dr. Martin: Fairchild-Schlumberger (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Thompson, Frederick B. (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Tomorrow/Today, San Jose Public Broadcasting System (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Turing, A. M. (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Tyler, Ralph (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - University of California at Los Angeles (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - University of California at San Diego (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - University of Massachusetts at Amherst (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - University of Pennsylvania #1 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - University of Pennsylvania #2 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - University of Pittsburgh (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - University of Rochester (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - University of Southern California (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - University of Utah (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Useem, Dr. Elizabeth (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Volberg, Rachel (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Von Neumann, John (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Waller, Robert H. (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Wang, William (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - West, Martha (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Whitmore, Tom #1 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Whitmore, Tom #2 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Whitmore, Tom #3 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Whitmore, Tom #4 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Wilson, Kenneth #1 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Wilson, Kenneth #2 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Winston, Patrick (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Wiorkowski, John J. (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Woods, William A. #1 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Woods, William A. #2 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Woods, William A. #3 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Woods, William A. #4 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Woods, William A. #5 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Wright, Patricia (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Xerox Corporation #1 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Xerox Corporation #2 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Xerox Corporation #3 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Yale University (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Yngve, Victor: University of Chicago. (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - York, Carl M. (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Yovits, M. C. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Subseries B. Professional contacts in business and academia
    This subseries includes correspondence and information which was at one time deemed to be confidential. Careful review has restricted some material, eg: files of correspondence with proposal reviewers; however, the majority of the documents are available to researchers.
    - Brown, John Seely (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - DeBaun, Vincent C.: MIT (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Dolby, James L. (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Dwyer, W. James (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Enthoven, Dr. Alain: Stanford Business School (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Fisher, Joseph A. ("Josh"): Yale. June-Sept. 1983 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Fisher, Joseph A. ("Josh"): Yale. Jan. 1983 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Giamo, Edward C. ("Biff") (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Jenks, Richard D.: IBM. Dec. 1983, May 1984 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Jenks, Richard D.: IBM. Nov. 1983 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Jenks, Richard D.: IBM. Meeting notes (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Kennedy, Roger G.: National Museum of American History (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Lederberg, Joshua #1 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Lederberg, Joshua #2 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Linde, Dr. Charlotte #1 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Linde, Dr. Charlotte #2 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Linde, Dr. Charlotte #3 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Lucasfilm: Abbott, Curtis (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Lucasfilm: Abbott, Curtis: Moorer, James ("Andy") (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Mahoney, Michael: Princeton. (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Mathews, Max V. (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Pierce, John R. (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - The Research Group (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Seed, John C. (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Shaw, Ward (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Spencer Foundation (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Stanford University #1 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Stanford University #2 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Stryker, Michael P. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Symmetric Computer Systems (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Trachtman, Paul: Smithsonian Magazine. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - University of California at Berkeley (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Weiner, John M. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Weissman, Ronald (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Subseries C. Curriculum Vitae
    Subseries C contains alphabetically arranged curriculum vitae of reviewers and grant applicants; it is unclear during what time period these files were maintained.
    - Index to names (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - A-Ba (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Be-Bu (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Ca-Cl (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Co-Ct (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - D-F (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Ga-Ge (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Gi-Gr (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Ha-He (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - I-Ka (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Ke-L (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - M (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - N-P (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - R (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Sc-Sh (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Si-Sw (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - T-V (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - W-Z (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Series 6. Materials received after June 30, 1988
  Series VI contains materials received after SDF ceased operation on June 30, 1988. The bulk of these materials consists of grant reports submitted after this date. Final reports, financial reports and products of grants made by SDF, but not completed prior to June 30, 1988, will be housed in order received by Stanford University Libraries until all grant periods have ended.
  - Subseries A. Benchmark series
    Subseries A contains the five books published in the SDF Benchmark Series by the MIT Press. Publication dates range from 1989 through 1991.
    - Brady, Michael, Robotics Science. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Matthews, Max V. and Pierce, John R., Current Directions in Computer Music Research. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Cohen, Philip R., et al, Intentions in Communications. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Schwartz, Eric L., Computational Neuroscience. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Sells, Peter, et al, Foundational Issues in Natural Language Processing. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B. SDF/RAND Closing contracts
    This subseries contains the contracts entered into by SDF and The RAND Corporation in June 1988.
    - SDF/RAND Closing Contracts Jun. 30, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Subseries C. Grant materials beyond June 30, 1988
    Subseries C includes all reports and grant products submitted from grants not completed by June 30, 1988.
    - Subsubseries 1. Financial reports
      - Grant Financial Reports, Aug. 1988-Dec. 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Grant Financial Reports, Feb. 1990-- [end] (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Subsubseries 2. Annual/final reports
      - G015c, 237[a,b,c] and 238a, Reports (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - G303, Reports (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - G346, 380[b,d,e] and 824[a,b,e], and 809, Reports (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Subsubseries 3. Grant products
      - Fox, G., et al, Solving Problems on Concurrent Processors. vol.1: General Techniques and Regular Problems, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - G359[a,b,d], Zipser, David. Papers received c. Dec. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - G407, Mason, Matthew. Papers received c. Feb. 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - G460i, Bresnan, Joan and Barbara Groz. William J. Poser, ed. Papers from the Second International Workshop on Japanese Syntax, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - G565, Bavel, Zamir. Protocol Conversion with Power Tier Automata, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - G565, Bavel, Zamir. Representing Turing Machines By Power Tier Automata and Power Tier Automata By Turing Machines, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)